# NM

#### CONTACT

migelmarshal@gmail.com

+97156-3982449

nigelmarshal.com

#### **EDUCATION**

### BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (WITH DISTINCTION): COMPUTER SYSTEMS

2015

Heriot-Watt University -School of Mathematical and Computer Sciences, Dubai, UAE

#### CODING

React

SCSS (BEM Naming)

HTML5

TypeScript

Javascript

PHP

git

webpack

npm

gulp

Sitecore

#### PROJECT MANAGEMENT

Agile Methodologies
JIRA

Trello

#### **DESIGN**

Sketch

Adobe Photoshop

Axure

#### **LANGUAGES**

English (Native) Hindi (Intermediate) Urdu (Intermediate) Malayalam (Intermediate)

## NIGEL MARSHAL

Front-End Engineer

#### **ABOUT**

I have six years of front-end development experience along with project & technical management experience; managing outsourced international development teams and handling client requests. Most recently I've been contracted as a front-end developer for ADDA where I worked on multiple government entity Sitecore websites and built modular components. I have a strong core in UX, having taken the HFI UX course and worked in one of the top MENA UX digital agencies as a UX Specialist/Developer. Over the course of my professional career I've worked with technologies such as React, HTML5, CSS3, ECMAScript (ES6, ES7 Javascript) and more, allowing me to build and deliver robust SPAs.

#### **EXPERIENCE**



#### FRONT-END CONSULTANT/DEVELOPER

Abu Dhabi Digital Authority (ADDA) / OMNIA | Dec 2019 - Present

- Worked within multiple development SCRUM teams to create numerous government entity Sitecore websites for the Abu Dhabi Government including but not limited to: ADCustom, EMI, QCC, HRA, WRD and ADInspires.
- Created custom HTML5 modular components for teams to integrate in subsites with customized branding themes.
- Created documentation for developed components and subsites to contribute to the development wiki accessed by multiple vendors.

#### dubizzle FRONT-END ENGINEER

dubizzle/OLX MENA | Jan 2019 - Nov 2019

- Worked as the sole front-end support for OLX MENA spanning 8 countries, including Lebanon, Egypt and Oman.
- Lead the front-end initiative to implement new paid product features for OLX MENA, to generate passive revenue for the company to boost users ad reach.
- Worked as an integral instructor on a code migration initiative, guiding international colleagues, helping them move to a more advanced and efficient system as well as assist with RTL support.
- Improved, optimized and converted outdated custom PHP MVC front-end technologies to more robust future proof code using React.
- Contributed to documentation and wikis for on-boarding new developers.

#### rbbi UX SPECIALIST & UX DEVELOPER

rbbi | Sept 2015 - Mar 2018

- Worked with the core development team in building fully responsive and comprehensive websites with a user centered approach.
- Worked as a hybrid Technical/Project manager liaising with outside vendors for timely client deliverables and code collaboration.
- Possess experience in the UX development workflow such as user research interviews, wire framing, requirement assessment, user testing, project management, development, QA and deployment.
- Handled client facing communications with regards to project progress, change requests and trouble shooting while spearheading development progress.
- Worked closely with cross departments including SEO, Analytics, CRO and Content for websites ranging from landing pages, WordPress websites, webapps and ecommerce.